hello and welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft now i am actually
in my normal base because i'm going to
be working on this room
uh for a little while because in my last
episode i left mumbo jumbo or mulbo
gumbo as he's now known during the civil
war i gave him some instructions you see
and those instructions were
very
very simple
they said press the button twice that's
all you had to do press the button twice
now watch watch this
oh
hit
button behind castle
number two
my instructions are imprinted on the
fish
so where's the castle number two alright
it could be one of these
no
oh there it is
that's so cool
that is so so cool anyway right orders
create a weapon for team star but rig it
to blow up when one of them uses it and
blames someone on the g team if they ask
right
spoon central as usual mumbo so to make
things
very clear to mumbo jumbo
we're gonna have to leave him another
message now
i don't even know he's probably gone and
done this the first orders properly
before reading the second book which is
not ideal at all but you know i'm
starting to think like we sent the wrong
man in
we should have sent someone else in to
be the mole uh but it is what it is and
i think the first thing that we're gonna
need to do
is leave mumbo a message
so that he really and i mean really can
not miss it let's head on over to his
base
and leave him a little message
that should be fairly obvious i think
this is a pretty important part so maybe
just over here
let's get started shall we what i
basically did because this took so long
to do i time lapsed it and i wrote mumbo
a message that i personally feel he
would have struggled to ignore
so i used a lot of blocks to write the
message in the air
right in his face and it's no no it's
not did you press the butt it's did you
press
the button
twice it's a very simple question that i
hope you will then understand
it may have taken well over an hour but
do you guys think he could miss this do
you do you really think like he could
misunderstand this
i mean
look he comes here a lot he should in
theory be able to see this and go did
you press
the button
twice the answer is no and hopefully he
will realize but
the fact that i now have to do this
to get mumbo to
do what he was told
it's ridiculous
oh my god i should have built a giant
spoon as well
but this took
well enough time
i can't believe this is what it's come
to but
eventually he'll get his orders
and hopefully fulfill them after that
the heck is this why is there a flashing
light oh it's on
on
it's buzz buzz
oh no
this isn't morse code is it
oh i have no idea how to do this how do
i know when it starts that's the real
question how do i know when it starts
yep
that's definitely timed
oh there we go it started it started it
started on
okay i'm gonna i'm gonna i'm gonna write
this down so i can make sure i get it
right okay i think i've been through it
several times now
and i think it goes dash dot dot dash
dash dash
dash dot
dot
i think i'm gonna put this in a morse
code translator because i have no idea
what it says this mumbo this took me
like 20 minutes
why did you do this
because what it says is d
o
n
e it says
done
[Laughter]
why couldn't you have made that so much
easier
well at least i actually understand
morse code a bit now
oh what a nightmare okay um i don't know
what to do with this maybe i should take
this down because it's a clock you know
and we don't want um too many clocks on
the server in case of lag i've i'm
pretty sure i've got the message i
actually messed up because
i i was reading it and i got like dash
dash or whatever and i was like d-w-n-e
no and i i got it wrong basically i
managed to work out through trial and
error
this would have taken mumbo like
10 20 30 minutes maybe to set up for
four letters and it took me 20 minutes
to decipher it
we've wasted about an hour of each
other's time
to say done wait
if he said he's done he's already done
the orders he's done the real orders
okay so let me get this straight i told
mumbo to hit the button twice he didn't
he did it once so he got the fake orders
and took it as real orders he then did
it
and then made the morse code thing to
say that he had done it i then realized
that he hasn't got the real orders and
i've built i've built this that thing
over there to say did you press the
button i feel like i feel like a teacher
that's realized that someone's done
their homework wrong did you look at
page 78 mumbo like i told you
no you didn't did you mumbo
anyway what i was trying to do
was use this layer as my storage
facility so one of the things that i
actually wanted to do was make it easier
to get in here because
going like down there and then round and
back up is super annoying so i was
thinking we could create like an archway
here so i can just fly in and out so i
have easy access to all of my gear which
is why i was also tidying this up i
added a trim around here in white and
then a trim in like gray around the
bottom and then i was going to do like a
pattern where it kind of goes maybe up
like that and sort of curls around i
don't know i'm not entirely sure yet but
either way i want to start
sort of finalizing the base because it's
taken a long time and i i have bought a
lot of wood to make a lot of chests and
i'm thinking i need to somehow
some way
create some sort of stack of chest that
uses these weird third sections that
i've got so maybe one section will be
there there and then maybe one two one
two and then i can divide it up so i can
think about this pretty carefully but i
think i'm gonna need some platforms as
well
i've made myself a couple of platforms
here and i've even done a really cool
little motif here i think this is like
rather inspired from the g team base but
because i've got exactly the same
palette it really works so i reckon if i
continue that all the way to the top
maybe add some on the sides here
and then somehow figure out how to make
a pattern like that on a shape like this
and i reckon this room would look really
really cool however i am wondering how
this storage is gonna work so it's
obviously not redstone i i don't think
i'm going to make a mass storage thing
even though that was in my overall plan
i just don't see it happening
the problem is i don't really have the
redstone capability of making it that's
that's the real problem
and i'm not sure that i would use anyway
because even in mumbo's redstone system
he just throws all the items in yeah and
then it sorts it for him great but he's
still got to go in and like open up all
the chests to find the stuff he knows
where they all are so
if i have like stacks of chests in this
sort of formation it could look really
cool
i'm not really sure what to do with this
gap here i could add just a chest here
but it doesn't look quite right
oh well
to be honest we've been playing
hermitcraft now for seven months
and i've been using that storage system
down there well the messy one
for seven months so i'm not sure it
makes that much difference what i do at
this point
i've added this really nice entrance as
well and i think with a few stacks of ah
actually you know what that's a really
nice effect if i actually put all of
these i don't like the gap between the
chests but if i add a filler block there
this could be a really nice effect the
whole thing and then i'll need to tidy
up that mess around there but yeah this
is definitely something i need to work
on in the background for sure
this is one of those jobs
this is one of those jobs that's needed
doing for a really long time but because
it's such a dull task moving items
around i've been putting it off
i think that's a pretty good start to
this room and then we'll see how it goes
from there but for now i've got a couple
of other things that i need to do
mumbo's actually just logged on so i'm
guessing that he's seen my
oh
what
what message okay maybe we we need we
need to discuss a few things with our
our model our man on the inside is he in
his base oh he's right there
hey mumbo my my mold friend
you're right uh how's it going
have you seen what i've done
yeah i mean i couldn't miss it did you
read the message before you blew it up
i yeah i mean yeah yeah yeah
i mean i managed to just about read it
but i was quite excited to blow it up so
i only got one look at it uh
did did it make sense did you did you
understand what i was trying to
communicate
now i know
i know i've messed up okay i'm i'm aware
that i've messed up but in the future
okay use the word twice as opposed to
times two yeah okay because i thought
you meant there was two castles i was
looking around
for the second castle for for a while
right
okay
i was so confused you know
i mean
come on man you need to explain this
sort of thing a little bit
so wait can you explain have you done
the fake mole report uh not yet
but that is that's on the way um i you
know i i have someone in mind that i can
i can talk to that i'll be able to
confess all to okay so you now have the
real mole report and you understand what
you're doing yeah i have lost it that
way it's not in my inventory anymore it
was somewhere i lost it
look just give me a second okay i've
lost i've
wait hang on hang on hang on it might be
in one of these chests um
please check discord by exuma no that's
not it
you know what it doesn't matter you know
what it said right
yep yeah so nothing
nothing could possibly go wrong
the main thing is you got to gain their
trust that's the main thing yep if that
means attacking us with them do it if it
means making things for them do it but
we need our man on the inside for when
it counts you know i'll tell you what we
need mumbo we need a key word like you
need to tell us
when they're attacking okay we need to
know if we're under attack that that is
something we can't tell
because we don't have the render
distance be able to see if they're
coming towards us yeah yeah so of course
something inconspicuous yeah yeah
something something that when you say in
chat
i know what it is you got a word
uh bananas i think but not bananas
aren't they going to be a little bit
suspicious that you're saying bananas in
chat
nah no i
i'm
i mean i'm sure it'll be fine like okay
just yeah just say it once in chat and
then like you'll be able to tell like
you'll be able to like play it off of
something like i don't know you're
checking for lag or something it'd be
easy yeah yeah
all right
oh man i should have got you have no
faith in me
i can feel it air
i think that's enough of working on that
room for now because there's actually a
lot that needs doing in the g-team base
i've even put my military uniform on you
can't really see it
but we need to go and trap up this
g-team base and i've started preparing
some of these false entrances on the
outside so that i can do the same sort
of thing that i did to iskall when he
was after me with the tag which was
absolutely hilarious i'm hoping we can
fool a couple of people here or there
but for now we really don't have much of
an official entrance we just have this
thing which
yeah it's not particularly great we're
going to replace this asap with a very
secret very secure
entrance to the base i love this thing i
i've got several outfits that i'm going
to be using over the course of this
fight
and this is one of them so this main
room is actually mostly done there's not
a lot we can do we can potentially add a
couple more traps but everything else is
severely undefended and we need to do
something about it
but i'm still in the process of moving
all of this
junk and that's what it is it's just
junk
so i've been slowly moving everything
here and this place in particular needs
lots and lots of traps and i think even
a second vault after this where we hide
the mega valuables and then even a
second a third volt after that so many
volts they won't know what's real and
what's not why is iskal wearing a
pokemon based skin
where is your uniform iskall just not
wearing it at the moment
it was very blue no dude you had the
best uniform as for traps in the base
i'm still trying to work out the best
way of doing these things because
there's actually so many places we can
trap we just have to be smart about it
because we don't want to waste time
trapping things that they may never use
these bubble elevators there's a high
likelihood they might use these so maybe
we could trap those unfortunately
there's just no space around them for
the redstone so we might need to use
things that are underground mainly to
trap things or we've got like this space
between the two areas that we can trap
there used to be a witch in here but
she's vanished
oh oh no that's the code word that's the
code word
need to message everyone that's online
stress
under attack join discord uh
who else is online on my team no oh my
goodness i should have seen this coming
with so many of them online right now
but mumbo's giving us the the warning
and there's i need to get them online
right now stress stress stress stress
okay no time no time no guys guys guys
guys guys get into the lobby right now
we have no time i must you did you see
mumbo say okay me and mumbo agreed on a
code word he's put bananas in chat that
means that an attack is incoming you
need to get
right um
me and you armory right now stress you
need to go upstairs get an invisibility
potion and uh bring all your dogs like
make them not sit okay you're gonna
you're gonna be the you're we we're not
gonna be out we're outnumbered oh yeah i
know i need to get rid of all my stuff
hang on
hurry up
okay we're gonna do the armor stand
trick everyone knows that one right yes
yes yes okay okay yes
oh i'm so stressed out you look good you
look good yeah you're like dude you're
looking shiny dude
why is he spamming bananas he only needs
to use this we have the worst mole in
the world guys he only needed to say it
once
what to be fair though he did alarm us
as well underneath us
i see them
and they can't see us right cause we're
invisible no we're invisible
we're invisible oh this is gonna be
yours i do i'm shaking they're gonna get
into the redstone room there so it's not
gonna be in the basement
they might pop through the wall
okay stress is doing some jumping this
is all on you
[Laughter]
mumbo we know
oh there they go they're they're going
through the case they're going through
the case right now i can see their faces
i can see their power ranger uniforms
they're wearing a squid head okay right
they're sneaking in they're sneaking in
they have no idea good
all right okay on your command
okay wow there are so many there's an oh
dude there's a baby piglet are you ready
yeah on your command yeah three
two
one
go
go go go go go go go go go go
[Laughter]
the wolves don't know what to do
she's dead order i got her
wow
these dogs were genius
oh bless them
who's your good boys who's your good
boys here go play with the ball play
with the ball
wait wait there's a guy right here
there's a guy running there's a squeaker
no no no
get stressed stress get docked get dark
get dark
[Laughter]
look at the dogs go
there's too many of them
oh my goodness
what is that all of this stuff oh is
that oh that's eustress i was wondering
why that squid head was bubbling around
we need to put that squid head on one of
the armor stands as a trophy the worst
infiltration attempt in history of
infiltrations
do we say gg and and you know
well
that is an overwhelming amount of wolves
you guys did not be honest like i saw it
i didn't even have to do anything
that was ridiculous yeah even though
they have failed in their attempt to
infiltrate our base
i think it's time that we went on the
offensive so i've gathered up a bunch of
stuff and i've got an idea on how we can
pay them back doesn't look like any of
them are online right now which is
perfect because i don't really want to
be interrupted or caught doing this
so i'm not going to be doing any damage
today and i actually need my elytra in
order to do this because it's going to
be a bit tricky you see i don't know how
functional this is going to be but we
need to make it first
so all i'm going to do
is make a big ring
that goes around
their base pretty much and i've got to
make sure there's plenty of straight
parts
and don't worry this is gonna make sense
very very quickly and hopefully i can
get this done before one of them logs on
i don't really want to get caught doing
this so it's not massive and that's
intentional but this wooden ring
is going to link up but i don't actually
want it to link up right now i just need
it to
circle back round for a second
i really hope that i'm i've thought this
through
and then we create a train track all the
way around all right i've got my train
track that goes all the way around maybe
some of you have already figured it out
but basically i've been really
interested in these laser beams with all
of these guardians in minecarts now
there's
easily there's got to be 10 in there
maybe more
so i'm going to commandeer them and take
them on a little journey up here so if
they try and use their cannons they've
got to deal with a bunch of guardians
circling them for a while which would be
really annoying
the only thing that bothers me is i've
got to get close in order to do this so
i've got to be very quick
so all right oh wait ha actually can
they not see me oh brilliant i might not
have to worry oh no yeah yep they see me
they see me okay well what if i just
take this invisibility potion
can they see me now
yup
yup yup invisibility means nothing to
these people they don't seem to have a
particularly good range that's why i've
made the ring around here not too big so
that they can if they're in the middle
of it like they'll still take some
damage i've got a little bit of
experience now using these carts
so i know that i basically need to have
this whole thing powered because getting
anything uphill is actually really
difficult now if i break anything around
here
i'm scared that this is gonna go
horribly wrong
and then they need a little nudge they
need a little nudge i think i did it i
think
uh
off they go
oh no
what the heck
i forgot one piece
oh
i can't believe it
i cannot believe it
i i
i cannot believe it i cannot believe it
i thought this was so foolproof
well there they are um
this is this is terrible
this is terrible thankfully there is
another one over there it just means
that this is slightly more difficult
than it needed to be
and away they go
oh i've done it
okay
off they go and i'm hoping that they'll
separate at some point
please don't get stuck
yes yes
okay now
all i need to do
oh no
no no no no no no no no no no no
no no no no
no no no no no no no no
all right
off you go no
come on off you go oh what the heck
oh
well some of some of them went up i
don't understand why they fell off all
right we got some of them that
that is gonna have to do
frustrating to say the least however if
i don't get my flight under control
these guys are not gonna loot properly
i think i've actually done more damage
than good here because most of their
guardians are now in a defensive place
inside their moat
which i imagine at one point is actually
going to hurt us quite a lot well at
least some of them have made it up there
but i've just got to tidy up this mess
beforehand don't want to leave this
lying around this looks really tacky
okay so basically if this happens again
when i try and push them
if they just fly off the end i'm not
going to be happy
oh it works perfectly well that's a
relief i did think that they would split
up at some point but nope they're still
cramming together like best friends so
if they tried to oh
okay if they try and take this down it
should be a real nightmare for them
um i'm hoping that they'll split up as
they go round over time maybe or if they
get interrupted
maybe i could try and interfere with
them but i'm so scared that they're just
gonna fly off
this wasn't nearly as successful as i
thought it was going to be
the main issue was most of them just
decided to fly off into the moat
really annoying but yeah that
that should be enough to keep them
occupied it's about the most that i can
manage with the time that i've got
because i've got to trap
a lot of our base and you'll see that
there's this little contraption up here
that we've used to collect a few things
for a few traps so i'll keep that a
little secret for next time but i'm
afraid that's all from me everybody i
hope you've enjoyed this episode and
hopefully we can get this war
done and dusted and out of the way
and claim a victory for the g team
but we've got to trap our base
absolutely insanely
so that we can make sure that we secure
the victory okay thank you very much for
watching everyone good bye